# Dinh Van Manh - Backend Developer

Phone: +84 90.626.9055

Email: manhit96@gmail.com

Github: <a href="https://github.com/imManhIT">https://github.com/imManhIT</a>

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Developer with 5 years experience. I have 2 year of experience in Backend Developer and 3 year of Android reverse engineering.

Learning new technologies and languages are my favorites. I self-taught Backend Development with MEAN stack, Nestjs and Laravel.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programing Languages: Javascript, Typescript, PHP, Java

#### Frameworks/Platforms:

- Nodejs, Expressjs, Nestjs
- Angular 2+
- Laravel
- Android

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

#### Others:

- Good understanding of OOP Programming, SOLID Principles
- Hand-on experience with Ubuntu/CentOS Server, Web Server (LEMP stack, MEAN stack)
- Hands-on experience with Android reverse engineering
- Hands-on experience with OpenCV, Google MK Kit (Android)
- Experience in using Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, ClickUp, Trello

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

<u>Freelancer</u> <u>03/2022 - Now</u>

Building 2 websites for individual customers, using Nodejs, Nestjs, MongoDB, Laravel, MySQL

### **Golden City - Head of IT Department**

02/2020 - 03/2022

Project: MobileCity Website, Sales and Warehouse Management System (8 members)

• **Description:** A top website selling electronics products, accessories and smartphone repair services in Vietnam, nearly 2 million users visit per month.

#### • Technologies:

- Backend: Laravel, MySQL, Redis, Nginx, PHP-FPM
- o Frontend: HTML/CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap

## Responsibilities:

- Participating in project upgrade MobilecCity website, Sales and Warehouse management software
- Discuss, analyze and identify things need improve
- Collect user requirements, business flows/rules
- Make the project specification document and wireframes

#### **Project: SNMS Phone farms (5 members)**

• **Description:** Android device control system, manage thousands of Android devices to perform actions that simulate user manipulation according to the script, for example: like, share, post on facebook, Google search, visit a website,...

#### • Technologies:

- Web frontend (admin dashboard): Typescript, Angular + ngxBootstrap
- Backend: Javascript, Nodejs, Express.js, SocketlO, Mongoose, MongoDB
- Client app (Android): Java, EventBus, SocketIO, ObjectBox, Promise,
  OpenCV, Google ML Kit

#### Responsibilities:

- Evaluating technologies, making design decision
- Define architecture, solutions, make the project specification document
- Build backend and participate in some core features of the client app (object/text recognition, Socket)
- Develop Google search and Web visit features (backend, frontend and client app)
- Setup, configuration backend/web server, database, deployment
- Maintain, refactor/improve the system

#### Project: MobileLog App (3 members)

 Description: Internal hotline tracking app, track call/sms history, call recording, support Android 12+

#### • Technologies:

Client (Android App): Java, Firebase, Magisk (Root)

- o Server: PHP, Yii Framework, Firebase, MySQL, Nginx, PHP-FPM
- o Web frontend: HTML/CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap

## • Responsibilities:

- Upgrade client app to supported Android 10/11/12
- Refactor call recorder module: solved call record permission problem on Android 10+, allow selection multiple audio sources and output encode format, helped the app compatible with more device models, give best call record quality

## S-Unlock - Founder

08/2018 - 01/2020

S-Unlock was the world's leading smartphone software and unlocking services provider at the time.

**Project:** S-Unlock.com (A top smartphone software and unlocking service website)

**Project:** SAMTool (A best sim unlocking tool for Samsung phones)

## **MobileCity - Mobile Phone Software Technicians**

01/2015 - 2018

## **EDUCATION**

**FPT Polytechnic (2014 - 2017)** 

Studying Software Development

## **PASTIMES AND ACTIVITIES**

- I'm reading the IT blog/website, learning new technologies and working on some favorite projects in my free time.
- I also like to play football, play some mobile game